Automated code review is one of the most
impactful ways that you can improve the
code quality coming out of your agent.
I've known this for a while, but it's
taken me a while to kind of implement it
and figure out a reusable skill that I
can give to people to review their code.
I've got this review skill here in my
skills repo, which is currently sitting
at whoa, 1,000
Sorry, 109,000 stars, and it is
currently marked as in progress. I'm
sort of okay with it, but I'm not
terribly happy with it. So, I've been
looking around for inspiration in other
skills that I can copy from, steal ideas
from, and one crossed my path I want to
show you. It is this one from the cursor
team. It is the thermonuclear code
quality review. Use this skill for an
unusually strict review focused on
implementation quality, maintainability,
abstraction quality, and code base
health. And one thing I think is notable
about this skill is how ambitious it
asks the reviewer to be. It's asking it
to be very ambitious and look for code
judo moves throughout the review. The
skill itself is simply one file. It's
just a skill.md
up here. And what I thought I'd do is I
would copy it to my local system, try it
out on some actual code of mine, and see
what it comes up with. Yesterday, I
spent a lot of time working on
Sandcastle, my open-source software
factory, and so I figure I would review
the last X number of commits and see
what it thought about them. So, I'm
going to be pretty loose here. I'm just
going to say thermonuclear code quality
review, review the last five PRs that
made it to main. I'm going to stick it
on auto mode, and while it's doing this,
let's actually go and read the skill
because that should explain the skill a
bit more.
So, it starts from this baseline.
Perform a deep code quality audit of the
current branches changes. Rethink how to
structure implement the changes to
meaningfully improve code quality
without impacting behavior. Work to
improve abstractions, modularity, reduce
spaghetti code, improve succinctness and
legibility. Be ambitious. If there is a
clear path to improving the
implementation that involves
restructuring some of the code base, go
for it. Be extremely thorough and
rigorous. Measure twice, cut once. What
I've often found with review skills like
this is that the agent is not ambitious
enough. If you pass an agent a diff,
then it will usually treat that diff as
its bounds within which it can work.
Whereas this prompt appears to be going
beyond that. It's essentially saying,
"Look throughout the entire code base
for opportunities, but starting from
this current current branch's changes."
It also goes on to add a bunch of
non-negotiable non-negotiable additional
standards. Be ambitious about structural
simplification. Again, the ambition. Do
not let a PR push a file from under 1K
lines to over 1K lines without a very
strong reason. This is really
interesting. I've actually reached this
conclusion myself as well. Large files
are just quite hard for agents to
navigate because they need to ingest the
entire file into their context window in
order to find the thing that's actually
useful within it. A much better way to
structure that is to split them into
multiple files and let the kind of the
file name of the file be the context
pointer that tells it what's in that
file and whether it might need to open
it. This ends up being a lot more
context efficient. I have generally
split my files if they go over 5K
tokens, but this 1K lines is sort of I
guess a similar rubric. Do not allow
random spaghetti growth in existing
code, okay? I see it's sort of arguing
against nesting here. If a change adds
weird if statements in random places,
treat that as a design problem, not a
stylistic nit. Prefer pushing the logic
into a dedicated abstraction, helper,
state machine, policy object, or
separate module instead of tangling an
existing path. Interesting. This is
another way of telling it to be
aggressive about, you know, if there's a
bunch of nested if statements and weird
conditionals, maybe abstract that into a
cleaner abstraction or a helper or
something. It's arguable whether I
prefer that. I suppose sometimes I do,
sometimes I don't, but let's assume it's
a good thing for now. Bias towards
cleaning the design, not just accepting
working code, again pushing it to be
ambitious. Prefer direct, boring,
maintainable code over hacky and magical
code. This is like a classic one in
these prompts. This comes from I think
simplify in Claude code. And not the
same wording I think, but a similar idea
that you want simple, direct code that's
easy to read. I really like this one
actually. Push hard on type and boundary
cleanliness when they affect
maintainability. So we're specifically
talking about types here. Question
unnecessary optionality, unknown, any,
or cast heavy code when a clearer type
boundary could exist. This is kind of
TypeScript focused here. Unknown and any
are specifically TypeScript
terms. And the unnecessary optionality
is one that always gets me. Whenever an
agent adds a prop onto a React
component, let's say, it always adds it
as optional. I don't know why. I don't
know why. It's so stupid. Even when it's
always required, it will add it as
optional just to make it backwards
compatible or something or to lessen the
blast radius of the change. So yeah,
question unnecessary optionality is a
great one. Keep logic in the canonical
layer and reuse existing helpers. Prefer
existing canonical utilities and helpers
over bespoke one-offs. Yes, I suppose
it's basically just telling it to look
for places where this has already been
solved in the code base and use those
instead. Makes sense. Treat unnecessary
sequential orchestration and non-atomic
updates as design smells when the
cleaner structure is obvious. If
independent work is serialized for no
good reason, ask whether the flow should
run in parallel instead. I see, this is
about performance essentially.
Obviously, when two things that are
independent, if they run in parallel,
then it's going to be faster than if
they run sequentially. So that's kind of
what it's going for here. But it's also
saying do not over-index on
micro-optimizations.
Okay, so it's basically telling it don't
go too far. I think if this was my
skill, I would definitely rewrite this
to be a lot more direct. Treat
unnecessary sequential orchestration and
non-atomic updates as design smells.
That's just word salad to me. I don't
know what that means. So, this is really
cool. Primary review questions for every
meaningful change ask, is there a code
judo move that would make this
dramatically simpler? That's great. I
love that. Can this be reframed so that
fewer concepts branch or helper layers
are needed? Lovely. I don't love this.
Does this improve or worsen the local
architecture? You've got to say exactly
what good and bad looks like to an agent
in order for improve or worsen to mean
anything. Overall, this set of questions
along with the kind of rules above give
the agent a nice kind of way into
talking about the code, which is what
you need. And now it talks about really
bad stuff. Escalate findings when you
see a complicated implementation where a
cleaner reframing could delete whole
categories of complexity. Refactors that
move code around but fail to reduce the
number of concepts a reader must hold in
their head. Yeah, there's a bit of
repetition going on here. Unnecessary
casts, any unknown or optional params.
What sort of scares me about these big
review-based prompts is that this is a
huge ball of mud for the agent to read.
Like there's a lot of instructions in
here and it's hard to know what to
prioritize for the agent. So, I don't
know. This this makes me a little bit
nervous. I do like this though. When you
identify a code quality problem,
perverse suggestions like delete a whole
layer of indirection rather than
polishing it. Again, ambitious. Split a
large file into smaller focused modules.
Again, you know, making things easier to
navigate for the agent. Again,
duplication. Make type boundaries more
explicit so the control flow gets
simpler. There's a lot of duplication
throughout a lot of this. This could be
cut down I think quite a lot. Review
tone. I don't know why this is here.
This is just sort of saying
choose your tone. I suppose. Be direct,
serious, and demanding about quality. Do
not be rude. This seems like a crazy
thing to add to a skill. I don't know
why that's here. What this does do is it
does really punch the language that the
agent should be using. So, we're really
emphasizing code judo, saying decompose,
pushes the file past, makes the
surrounding code more spaghetti. I like
that. But the down we can say output
expectations. Right, this is nice. It's
saying to prioritize findings in this
order. It's saying to float the
important stuff to the top. And
legibility and maintainability concerns
are at the bottom, structural code
quality regressions right at the top.
Right, and it is asking for an approval
here. So, it's approving or rejecting
the PR. And again, tons and tons of
repetition here. This skill could be a
lot shorter. So, what we have is a large
block of text that basically says, "Be
more ambitious. Here are some specific
things that you can focus on in your
review. Really go nuts here and like uh
propose a ton of structural changes.
Make sure that you uh prioritize your
findings in a certain order so you don't
flood it with useless crap, and then
approve or reject based on these
conditions." What I don't like here is
there's no mention of testing. There's
no mention of seams. There's no mention
of any kind of like improving the
feedback loops to make future runs
better, which in my view is the entire
point now of having a good code base or
having a code base that's easy to change
and modular and easy to navigate. All of
this appears to be focused on actual
source code, none of it on tests.
Interesting. But, okay, let's read what
it said here. So, it's taken the last
five PRs to main, and it has found some
blocker class structural issues. Okay,
it's found that an init service is now a
big file, so it's over 1,000 lines, and
it mixes a bunch of stuff here, and it
should have been preceded by a split,
and it's proposed an I split there. Ooh,
it's also trying to create an
abstraction here, a little make registry
generic function. Returning this would
delete 20 lines of duplicated
boilerplate for the same time. Feels
good. That's nice. So, we now go to the
next one. The feature specific if issue
tracker name custom scattered across
three layers. Interesting. It's
basically saying that instead of this
being a special case if statement here,
we should instead do a bit of code judo
and push the custom tracker variations
into a type itself, and then it can be
read later. I think in terms of
suggestions here, I happen to know this
code quite well. I think we are at two
out of two here. That's um seems like
two really good suggestions. Down here
we have an inconsistent contract
template args carries both shell
commands and prose markers. It's
basically saying that some of these are
runnable, but some of these are not
runnable here. And it's saying that
maybe we should widen the type to either
a command or a to-do marker
discriminated union or use a different
field entirely for unfilled markers. So
it's basically it's basically trying to
strengthen the type boundary here so
that we don't later pass in a prose
marker into something else. That's
interesting. I think that this comes
from an inaccurate understanding of the
whole system, which is okay. You're
going to get some false positives. I
suppose it's a false positive in any
review prompt. So this is the kind of
thing if it came up in a PR, I would say
this is fine. Don't worry about it. So
two out of three, not bad. Let's go look
at the strong code quality issues. Aha,
we do have a weird bug here that it's
found or not a bug, just a weird bit of
code design. We essentially have
different templates in Sandcastle that
each declare the dependencies that they
need and mostly they declare Zod as the
dependency. So we have this weird code
path in here that looks like it just
hard codes Zod and then interesting.
What Yeah, overall this is quite hard to
explain, but it's definitely pulled up
something weird here. So I think we're
at three out of four, which is good. Oh,
it's found some swallowed errors here.
Exec sync inside effect. sync with
swallowed errors. Interesting. We can
see it's trying something inside here
and if it fails, then it just like
returns false inside here. So yeah, this
is definitely another thing that I would
like the reviewer to look at. Looks like
we started decomposing a large file into
small files, but only half finished. So
this again is a good one. This is five
out of six so far. And it's now saying
there's a bit of prompt duplication
within some prompts that were changed
here. So the change is bite identical
for two different prompts here. It's
saying that we should refactor those
into a issue list preamble. I don't
think that's right. I think the prompts
should just be independently
changeable. So, not bad though, five out
of seven. Then, it's got a list of
smaller items worth fixing here. I've
done a quick scan and I would say most
of those look pretty good. And
interesting, I'm kind of intrigued by
the approval bar here. Under the skill
stated bar, a couple of the PRs should
not have landed in their current shape.
The behavior is correct in all three
substantive PRs, but the code base is
meaningfully messier than it was a week
ago.
>> [laughter]
>> Well, cool. I mean, we got some really
good feedback from this skill, I think.
I think what this is teaching me is that
actually getting the review to be super
ambitious and getting it to push a lot
of different options
will give you more false positives, but
those false positives are pretty easy
just to say no to, right? It's the ones
that you miss, that you never know
about, the opportunity for improvement
that you never see, those are the
dangerous ones. Overall, I would clean
up this skill so it's not quite so
duplicative, so there's, you know, a bit
more dry. And I would also just get it
to focus a lot more on tests, as well.
Think about the seams in your code base,
kind of like what my improved code base
architecture does. But overall, I think
this is worth pulling down,
experimenting with, and just seeing what
comes out of it. Now, if you dig this
stuff, then I'm running a cohort
starting next week, starting June 1st,
on AI coding for real engineers. This
has been my most subscribed to course
ever. People are going nuts for this.
We're going to have, I think, around
4,000, 4,500 people in there. So, yeah,
it's absolutely wild. But if you're
enjoying this stuff, if there's a skill
that you want me to review, I really
like making that content because it lets
me steal ideas from other people's great
skills, then let me know. Nice work, and
I'll see you very soon.